<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Interlisp Medley</title><link>/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Interlisp Medley</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>News</title><link>/page/news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/page/news/</guid><description>This page is for project news. Periodic updates of news since the (11/15/21) Annual Report.
1/2022 (draft in progress) Merry Christmas and Happy New Year
Steve&amp;rsquo;s Medley Interlisp: The Interactive Environment reformated for easier online reading. Joining the Software Preservation Network. Interlisp.online progress, changes expected New User documentation Still awaiting California Franchise Tax Board (FTB) to confirm exempt status (ETA April) work on Lisp-based GitHub client, comparison of Lisp files 12/2021 Interlisp Online: Run Medley Interlisp in the cloud with just a browser.</description></item><item><title>Interlisp Online</title><link>/page/online/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/page/online/</guid><description>Interlisp Online provides access to a version of Medley running in the cloud. All that is needed to get started is to create an account - simply an email address and password. Once an account has been created you can log in and start a Medley Interlisp session.
Sessions are preserved for an indefinite time (we haven&amp;rsquo;t worked out for how long &amp;ndash; after 30 days of inactivity?). But it should be good for experimenting and introducing yourself to the environment.</description></item><item><title>What is Medley Interlisp</title><link>/page/whatIsMedley/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/page/whatIsMedley/</guid><description>Medley Interlisp is the environment originally developed for the Xerox Lisp machines (called D-machines, names Dorado, Dolphin, Dandelion, Daybreak). The project was spun out to a company called Envos, which then turned into Venue.
It was the first IDE with a window/mouse/menu GUI, launched as a product from Xerox in 1980. It was a base from which AI applications were built, as well as a research project in its own right.</description></item><item><title>About the Medley Interlisp Project</title><link>/page/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/page/about/</guid><description>Our aim is to restore Medley Interlisp to usability on modern systems, sufficient to allow someone to develop some code and experience what it was like. You could think of this as a kind of &amp;ldquo;vintage software&amp;rdquo; project, to try to capture the sense of fluidity in the development cycle. We hope to provide a platform for demonstration of early experiments of hypertext (Notecards), Desktop management (Rooms), Object-oriented programming (LOOPS), as well as Interlisp itself.</description></item><item><title>Basic Components</title><link>/page/basic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/page/basic/</guid><description>An implementation of the virtual machine (like a port of the microcode that turned the Xerox hardware into a lisp machine.) The emulator, called maiko, was initially developed at Fuji Xerox for the SunOS/SPARC. It was subsequently ported to many different OS and hardware combinations.
The Lisp system itself was split into layered parts:
The core of the system written in Lisp to implement system components including memory management, Interlisp and Common Lisp interpreters and compilers.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Integration</title><link>/page/github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/page/github/</guid><description>There is a GitHub Organization Interlisp with repositories for Maiko, Medley, this web site (Interlisp.github.io) and others. The Wiki, Releases, Issues, Discussions, are all under the Medley repository. Objectives
The primary focus of this project is to make Medley usable enough that people can use it in a modern environment. Primarily this is a matter of testing and debugging; raise issues in the Interlisp/medley repo. But we&amp;rsquo;re also trying to &amp;ldquo;modernize&amp;rdquo; some things; for example, we&amp;rsquo;re adding Unicode support for IO (Interlisp-D was built before Unicode, and supports an older Xerox encoding).</description></item><item><title>Releases</title><link>/page/releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/page/releases/</guid><description>We have yet to do any formal releases, but there are some samples in the Medley repo. Download the medley tgz and maiko for your host OS and architecture. Or build your own maiko following the build instructions. Bibliography
Bibliography</description></item><item><title>History</title><link>/page/history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/page/history/</guid><description>To facilitate revision, the History section of the web site has been moved. See
Interlisp Timeline, History There is also a separate Interlisp History repository for older snapshots of Interlisp implementations and documentation.</description></item></channel></rss>