<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Interlisp Medley</title><link>https://stumbo.github.io/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Interlisp Medley</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://stumbo.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>News</title><link>https://stumbo.github.io/page/news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stumbo.github.io/page/news/</guid><description>The 2021 Medley Interlisp Annual Report provides a detailed report on 2021 accomplishments.
Recent Updates 3/2022 Interlisp Online new version! Many new/improved features. From any (recent) browser. Medley is running &amp;ldquo;in the cloud&amp;rdquo; and you connect to it (and your account) over the web. Medley Documentation. We&amp;rsquo;ve been updating the online documentation at least for getting started &amp;ndash; instructions on Running in various contexts and Building and Using. Interlisp.Org has been approved as tax-exempt by California Franchise Tax Board and the California AG, State Charity Registration Number: CT0278267 We have joined (as an &amp;ldquo;implementation sponsor&amp;rdquo;) the Software Preservation Network.</description></item><item><title>Interlisp Online</title><link>https://stumbo.github.io/page/online/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stumbo.github.io/page/online/</guid><description>Interlisp Online provides access to a version of Medley running in the cloud. All that is needed to get started is to create an account - simply an email address and password. Once an account has been created you can log in and start a Medley Interlisp session.
Sessions are preserved for an indefinite time (we haven&amp;rsquo;t worked out for how long &amp;ndash; after 30 days of inactivity?). But it should be good for experimenting and introducing yourself to the environment.</description></item><item><title>What is Medley Interlisp</title><link>https://stumbo.github.io/page/whatIsMedley/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stumbo.github.io/page/whatIsMedley/</guid><description>Medley Interlisp is the environment originally developed for the Xerox Lisp machines (called D-machines, names Dorado, Dolphin, Dandelion, Daybreak). The project was spun out to a company called Envos, which then turned into Venue.
It was the first IDE with a window/mouse/menu GUI, launched as a product from Xerox in 1980. It was a base from which AI applications were built, as well as a research project in its own right.</description></item><item><title>About the Medley Interlisp Project</title><link>https://stumbo.github.io/page/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stumbo.github.io/page/about/</guid><description>Goal Our aim is to restore Medley Interlisp to usability on modern systems, sufficient to allow someone to develop some code and experience what it was like. You could think of this as a kind of &amp;ldquo;vintage software&amp;rdquo; project, to try to capture the sense of fluidity in the development cycle.
We hope to provide a platform for demonstration of early experiments of hypertext (Notecards), Desktop management (Rooms), Object-oriented programming (LOOPS), as well as Interlisp itself.</description></item><item><title>Releases</title><link>https://stumbo.github.io/page/releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stumbo.github.io/page/releases/</guid><description>Medley repo releases contains the current Medley release. New releases are generated regularly as functionality is restored and extended.
An alternative is to point your browser to Online Interlisp and try our cloud hosted version of Medley Interlisp.</description></item><item><title>Basic Components</title><link>https://stumbo.github.io/page/basic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stumbo.github.io/page/basic/</guid><description>An implementation of the virtual machine (like a port of the microcode that turned the Xerox hardware into a lisp machine.) The emulator, called maiko, was initially developed at Fuji Xerox for the SunOS/SPARC. It was subsequently ported to many different OS and hardware combinations.
The Lisp system itself was split into layered parts:
The core of the system written in Lisp to implement system components including memory management, Interlisp and Common Lisp interpreters and compilers.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Integration</title><link>https://stumbo.github.io/page/github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stumbo.github.io/page/github/</guid><description>There is a GitHub Organization Interlisp with repositories for Maiko, Medley, this web site (Interlisp.github.io) and others. The Wiki, Releases, Issues, Discussions, are all under the Medley repository.</description></item><item><title>History</title><link>https://stumbo.github.io/page/history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stumbo.github.io/page/history/</guid><description>To facilitate revision, the History section of the web site has been moved. See
Interlisp Timeline, History There is also a separate Interlisp History repository for older snapshots of Interlisp implementations and documentation.</description></item></channel></rss>